Nothing is stronger than family.
Fast & Furious Presents: Hobbs & Shaw is a action,
adventure, comedy film directed by David Leitch.
Ever since US Diplomatic Security Service Agent Hobbs and lawless outcast Shaw
first faced off, they just have traded smack talk and body blows.
But when cyber-genetically enhanced anarchist Brixton's ruthless actions
threaten the future of humanity, they join forces to defeat him.
Luke Hobbs, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Deckard Shaw, played by Jason Statham.
Brixton, played by Idris Elba.
Hattie Shaw, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Queenie Shaw, played by Helen Mirren.
Madame M, played by Eiza González.
Hobbs & Shaw (marketed as Fast & Furious Presents: Hobbs & Shaw) is a 2019 American buddy action
comedy film directed by David Leitch from a script by Chris Morgan and Drew Pearce.
It is a spin-off film and the ninth installment of the Fast & Furious franchise,
taking place after the events of The Fate of the Furious (2017).
It stars Dwayne Johnson and Jason Statham, alongside Idris Elba, Vanessa
Kirby, Eiza González, Cliff Curtis, and Helen Mirren.
In the film, Luke Hobbs and Deckard Shaw join Shaw's younger sister Hattie Shaw to take down Brixton Lore
(Elba), a cybernetically enhanced terrorist, who is threatening the world with a deadly virus.
Franchise star and producer Vin Diesel said in 2015 that possible spin-offs were in early
development, and Hobbs & Shaw was officially announced in October 2017.
Leitch signed on to direct in April 2018, with Kirby and
Elba joining the cast three months later.
Principal photography ran from September 2018 to January 2019, with
locations including London, Glasgow, and Kauaʻi.
The film was subject to controversy after longterm
Fast & Furious producer Neal H.
Moritz filed a lawsuit against Universal Pictures for breach of oral contract and committing promissory fraud related to his role
on Hobbs & Shaw, which was eventually settled in September 2020 and he received a producer credit on F9 (2021).
An international co-production between the United States and Japan, Hobbs & Shaw premiered at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood
on July 13, 2019, and was theatrically released by Universal Pictures in the United States on August 2, 2019.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its action sequences and the chemistry between
Johnson and Statham, but found it underwhelming when compared to other Fast & Furious films.
It was a box office success, grossing $760.7 million
worldwide on a budget of $200 million.
The film explores themes of london, england, biological
weapon, secret organization, family clan, friends.
The tone is lighthearted.